Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Hazelton, Roger
    - "Salvation Through Worship." The Journal of Liberal Religion 5:3 (Winter 1944): 115-122. (Box 43)
    - "Review of The Scientific Spirit and Democratic Faith." The Philosophical Review 54:6 (November 1945): 617-618. (Box 43)
    - "Is a Christian Philosophy Possible?" Christendom 12:1 (Winter 1947): 1-9. (Box 43)
    - "God and the Soul: Augustine on the Devotional Life." The Journal of Religion 27:2 (April 1947): 91-101. (Box 43)
    - "Hebrew Religious Thought in Its Wider Cultural Context." Christendom 12:3 (Summer 1947): 390-392. (Box 43)
    - "Review of Seeds of Redemption by Bernard Eugene Meland." The Review of Religion 13 (January 1949): 202-205. (Box 43)
    - "Ecumenicity in worship." Southworth Lecture, May 4, 1949. [Also appears in "Ecumenicity in worship." RELIGION IN LIFE 19 (Winter 1949): 40-52; and ANDOVER NEWTON BULLETIN 42 (February 1950): 1-21.] (Box 43)
    - "Ecumenicity in worship." RELIGION IN LIFE 19 (Winter 1949): 40-52. [Also appears in ANDOVER NEWTON BULLETIN 42 (February 1950): 1-21.] (Box 43)
    - "The nature of Christian paradox." THEOLOGY TODAY 6 (October 1949): 324-355. (Box 43)
    - "Time, eternity, and history." JOURNAL OF RELIGION 30/1 (January 1950): 1-12. (Box 43)
    - "Providence and history." RELIGION IN LIFE 20 (Autumn 1951): 530-540. (Box 43)
    - "Liturgy and theology." DUKE DIVINITY SCHOOL BULLETIN 16 (February 1951): 8-19. (Box 43)
    - "Les Chretiens americains et la paix." FOI EDUCATION (July 1952): 127-130. (Box 43)
    - "The pastoral prayer--its purpose and effect." PASTORAL PSYCHOLOGY 4 (September 1953): 27-32. (Box 43)
    - "Providence and the mystery of God." CHICAGO THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY REGISTER 43 (March 1953): 1-9. (Box 43)
    - "A problem for liturgical and ecumenical theology." THEOLOGY TODAY 10 (July 1953): 196-207. (Box 43)
    - "Pascal and Jesus Christ." JOURNAL OF RELIGION 35 (April 1955): 65-73. (Box 43)
    - "Bibliography on Pascal." GENERAL THEOLOGICAL LIBRARY BULLETIN 47 (July 1955): 4-11. (Box 43)
    - "What is worship?" CHILDREN'S RELIGION 17 (February 1956): 3-4. (Box 43)
    - "Why pray?" International Journal of Religious Education 32:6 (February 1956): 5-6. (Box 43)
    - "Existentialism--an example." CONGREGATIONAL LIBRARY BULLETIN 8:2 (January 1957): 4-9. (Box 43)
    - The Church's Life: A Study Guide for the Laity on the Church and the Bible. The Evangelical and Reformed Church/The Congregational Christian Churches, 1957-1960. (Box 43)
    - "The conversation between art and Christian faith." THEOLOGY AND LIFE 1 (November 1958): 267-276. (Box 43)
    - "Memory, action and hope." CHILDREN'S RELIGION 21 (May 1960): 3-4. (Box 44)
    - "Servants of the church." UNITED CHURCH HERALD 3 (December 15, 1960): 12-13, 30. (Box 44)
    - "What is prayer?" CHILDREN'S RELIGION 21 (April 1960): 3-4. (Box 44)
    - "And gladly teach--the ministry reconsidered." THE CHICAGO SEMINARY REGISTER 50 (November 1960): 1-6. (Box 44)
    - "Highlights of the New Delhi Assembly." UNITED CHURCH HERALD 4 (December 28, 1961): 8-10. (Box 44)
    - "An infinite accent." MINISTER'S QUARTERLY 17 (Winter 1961-62): 20-23. (Box 44)
    - "Man and the gospel belong together." HARTFORD QUARTERLY 3:1 (Autumn 1962): 6-13. [Also delivered as a sermon at Oberlin Graduate School of Theology, December 2, 1962.] (Box 44)
    - "Review of Living Options in Protestant Theology by John B. Cobb, Jr." The Westminster Bookman 21:4 (December 1962): 14-15. (Box 44)
    - "What's right with the church?" UNITED CHURCH HERALD 5 (November 1, 1962):4-5. [Expanded transcript dated 7/12/1964.] (Box 44)
    - "The significance of Christian theology for adult education." In WIDER HORIZONS IN CHRISTIAN ADULT EDUCATION: SELECTED ADDRESSES AND PAPERS PRESENTED IN A WORKSHOP ON CURRICULUM OF CHRISTIAN EDUCATION FOR ADULTS. Pittsburg, PA (June 19-30, 1961):169-184. ed. Lawrence G. Little. Pittsburg: University of Pittsburg Press, 1962. (Box 44)
    - "On sharing God's love for the world." (unpublished) Sermon preached at Robbenolt ordination 9/27/1963. (Box 44)
    - "What's right with the church?" Expanded transcript dated 7/12/1964. [Originally publishd in UNITED CHURCH HERALD 5 (November 1, 1962):4-5.] (Box 44)
    - "In a time of turmoil." UNITED CHURCH HERALD 7 (December 1, 1964):12-13. (Box 44)
    - "Ministry as servanthood." (unpublished) A chapel meditation at Oberlin College, September 24, 1964. (Box 44)
    - "Review of Sacred and Profane Beauty: The Holy in Art by Gerardus van der Leeuw." Religion in Life 33/2 (Spring 1964): 305-306. (Box 44)
    - "Introduction to Oberlin College Choir Easter Service." (unpublished). April 13, 1965. (Box 44)
    - "Testing and holding fast." THE CHURCH ADVOCATE 130 (August 14, 1965):8-11. [Baccalaureate sermon preached at Findlay College, May 30, 1965.] (Box 44)
    - ¡"Mary belongs to Christmas." UNITED CHURCH HERALD 8 (December 1, 1965):5-7. (Box 44)
    - "Review of Style and Content in Christian Art by Jane Dillenberger and Contemporary Theatre and the Christian Faith by Kay M. Baxter." Religion in Life 35/2 (Spring 1966): 309. (Box 44)
    - "The face of theological education." THE EDUCATIONAL RECORDER 46 (Summer 1965):217-222. [Also published in MINISTER'S QUARTERLY 21 (Fall 1965):14-19.] (Box 44)
    - "The face of theological education." MINISTER'S QUARTERLY 21 (Fall 1965):14-19. [Also published in THE EDUCATIONAL RECORDER 46 (Summer 1965):217-222.] (Box 44)
    - "On becoming a believer." (unpublished) A sermon preached at Schwab Auditorium at Wellesley College, November 14, 1965. (Box 44)
    - "The future of God." McCORMICK QUARTERLY 19 (May 1966):267-274. [Also in ANDOVER NEWTON QUARTERLY 6 (January 1966):7-14.; and in THE MEANING OF THE DEATH OF GOD, ed. Bernard Murchland. New York: Random House, 1967.] (Box 44)
    - "The Bothersome Bishop." The New Republic 157/15 (October 7, 1967): 32-33, 36. (Box 44)
    - "Pascal and France." ANDOVER NEWTON QUARTERLY 8 (November 1967):101-114. (Box 44)
    - "The world of human grandeur and misery." (unpublished) The Lowell Lectures, Boston University School of Theology, March, 1967. (Box 44)
    - "The world of science." (unpublished) The Lowell Lectures, Boston University School of Theology, March, 1967. (Box 44)
    - "The world of the transcendent." (unpublished) The Lowell Lectures, Boston University School of Theology, March, 1967. (Box 44)
    - "The Diaconate in a United Church." Mid-Stream 8:1 (Fall 1968): 74-87. (Box 44)
    - "Is an empirical Christology possible?" In THE FUTURE OF EMPIRICAL THEOLOGY. ed. Bernard E. Meland. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1969: 221-234. (Box 44)
    - "Review of The Spirit and the Forms of Love by Daniel Day Williams." Union Seminary Quarterly Review 24:4 (Summer 1969): 390-394. (Box 44)
    - "Knowing the living God." (unpublished) [An address given at the American Baptist Convention, Christian Education Dinner, Seattle, May 16, 1969.] (Box 44)
    - "Where art and faith meet." NEXUS (Boston University School of Theology Alumni magazine) 8 (Winter 1970): 7-10, 32-24. (Box 44)
    - "Review of The Image of Man in C. S. Lewis by William Luther White." Journal of the American Academy of Religion 38/3 (September 1970): 316-317. (Box 44)
    - "On Christian worldliness." (unpublished sermon delivered March 28, 1971 at American Church in Paris.) (Box 44)
    - "Homo capax Dei: thoughts on man and transcendence." THEOLOGICAL STUDIES 33 (December 1972):735-747. (Box 44)
    - "Review of A Process Christology by David R. Griffin." Theology Today 31/2 (July 1974): 172, 174. (Box 44)
    - "Commentary on the statement [of faith]." In HISTORY AND PROGRAM. UCC Press, 1974, 37-38. (Box 44)
    - "Relocating Transcendence." UNION SEMINARY QUARTERLY REVIEW 30 (Winter-Summer 1975): 101-109. (Box 44)
    - "Life has the Last Word." (Unpublished sermon at The Second Church, Newton, March 16, 1975). (Box 44)
    - "Tillich's definitive bibliography." THE NEW REVIEW OF BOOKS AND RELIGION 1 (September 1976): 5. (Box 44)
    - "Toward a theology of courage." THE NEW REVIEW OF BOOKS AND RELIGION 2 (September 1977): 4. (Box 44)
    - "Can music be a holy act?" (unpublished address given at Virgil Thompson celebration, Church of the Epiphany, New York, NY, May 7, 1977). (Box 44)
    - "Theological analogy and metaphor." SEMEIA 13 (1978): 155-176. (Box 44)
    - "On Christian worldliness." (unpublished sermon delivered March 28, 1971 at American Church in Paris.) (Box 44)
    - "Christ without God or how to get around Chalcedon." (unpublished paper.), no date (Box 44)
    - Hymns and Worship. Boston: The Hymnal Committee, Pilgrim Press Division, Board of Home Missions., no date (Box 44)
    - "Theology and the ministry." (Unpublished paper)., no date (Box 44)
    - "Don't be anxious: sermon on Luke 12:22-31." (unpublished)., no date (Box 44)
    - "The grotesque, theologically considered." Society for Arts, Religion and Contemporary Culture. (Unpublished paper)., no date (Box 44)
    - Bibliography of Roger Hazelton, no date (Box 44)
    - THE GOD WE WORSHIP. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1946. (Box 45)
    - RENEWING THE MIND: AN ESSAY IN CHRISTIAN PHILOSOPHY. New York: Macmillan Company, 1949. (Box 45)
    - ON PROVING GOD: A HANDBOOK IN CHRISTIAN CONVERSATION. New York: Harper, 1952. (Box 45)
    - GOD'S WAY WITH MAN: VARIATIONS ON THE THEME OF PROVIDENCE. New York: Abingdon Press, 1956. [Also published as PROVIDENCE: A THEME WITH VARIATIONS. London: SCM Press, 1958.] (Box 45)
    - "The communion of the Holy Spirit." In GREAT PHRASES OF THE CHRISTIAN LANGUAGE: A DOCTRINAL BOOK. Philadelphia: The United Church Press, 1958. (Box 45)
    - NEW ACCENTS IN CONTEMPORARY THEOLOGY. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1960. (Box 45)
    - FORMULATING OUR BELIEFS. Teacher's Edition. Published jointly by the Christian Education Press of Philadelphia and the Pilgrim Press of Boston, 1961. (Box 45)
    - NEW TESTAMENT HERITAGE. Philadelphia: United Church Press, 1962. (Box 45)
    - CHRIST AND OURSELVES: A CLUE TO CHRISTIAN LIFE TODAY. First Edition. New York: Harper and Row, 1965. (Box 45)
    - NEW ACCENTS IN CONTEMPORARY THEOLOGY. New York: Harper Chapel Edition, 1965. (Box 46)
    - A THEOLOGICAL APPROACH TO ART. Nashville: Abingdon, 1967. (Box 46)
    - KNOWING THE LIVING GOD. Valley Forge: Judson Press, 1968. (Box 46)
    - THE WAYS OF CREATIVITY. New York: Division of Publications, United Church Board for Homeland Ministries for the Executive Council and the Theological Commission of the United Church of Christ, 1968. (Box 46)
    - BLAISE PASCAL: THE GENIUS OF HIS THOUGHT. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1974. (Box 46)
    - GRACEFUL COURAGE. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1985. (Box 46)
  - Heim, Stephen Mark
    - IS CHRIST THE ONLY WAY? CHRISTIAN FAITH IN A PLURALISTIC WORLD .Valley Forge: Judson Press, 1985. (Box 47)
    - SMH and Theodore Stylianopuolos, ed. SPIRIT OF TRUTH:ECUMENICAL PERSPECTIVES ON THE HOLY SPIRIT, PAPERS OF THE HOLY SPIRIT CONSULATION COMMISSION OF FAITH AND ORDER,NCCCUSA OCTOBER 24-23, 1985. Holy Cross Press, 1985. (Box 47)
    - SALVATIONS: TRUTH AND DIFFERENCE IN RELIGION. Maryknoll, NY: Orbis Books, 1995. (Box 47)
    - S. M. Heim, ed. GROUNDS FOR UNDERSTANDING: ECUMENICAL RESOURCES FOR RESPONSES TO RELIGIOUS PLURALISM. Grand Rapids: W.B. Eerdmans Publishing Company, 1998. (Box 47)
    - The Depth of the Riches: A Trinitarian Theology of Religious Ends (Grand Rapids, MI, Cambridge, UK: William B. Eerdmans Publishing Company, 2001). (Box 48)
    - Saved From Sacrifice: A Theology of the Cross. Grand Rapids: William B.Eerdmans Publishing Company, 2006. (Box 48)
  - Herrick, Everett Carleton
    - "By whose authority?" ROCHESTER THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY BULLETIN 75th year (June 1927): 538–548. (Box 49)
    - "Andover and Newton in commencement." THE CONGREGATIONALIST 116 (June 18, 1931):832–834. (Box 49)
    - [Statement on "real purpose and aim of a theological seminary."] CROZER QUARTERLY XVIII (April 1941): 89–90. (Box 49)
    - "Everett Carleton Herrick." ANDOVER NEWTON THEOLOGICAL SCHOOL BULLETIN 38 (June 1946). (bound commemorative volume). (Box 49)
    - TURNS AGAIN HOME. Boston: The Pilgrim Press, 1949. (Box 49)
    - "Church administration: bibliography." BULLETIN OF THE GENERAL THEOLOGICAL LIBRARY XLII (January 1950): 5–11. (Box 49)
    - "Elder John Leland." (typescript of thesis), no date (Box 49)
  - Hewitt, Emily
    - Bibliography of Hewitt, Emily., no date (Box 33)
  - Holladay, William L
    - [translation of Parts 1 and 2] "A Poor and Carefree Stranger." Girl Scout Pocket Songbook, Girl Scouts of the USA, 1956. (Box 50)
    - "Prototype and Copies: A New Approach o the Poetry-Prose Problem in the Book of Jeremiah." Journal of Biblical Literature 79/4 (1960): 351–367. (Box 50)
    - "On Every High Hill and Under Every Green Tree." Vetus Testamentum 11/2 (1961): 170–176. (Box 50)
    - "Style, Irony, and Authenticity in Jeremiah." Journal of Biblical Literature 81/1 (1962): 44–54. (Box 50)
    - "The So-Called 'Deuteronomic Gloss' in Jer. VIII 19b." Vetus Testamentum 12/4 (1962): 494–498. (Box 50)
    - Blauw, Johannes, translated W. L. Holladay, A. M. Chirgwin, and J. Slomp. The Missionary Nature of the Church: A Survey of the Biblical Theology of Mission. New York: McGraw Hill, 1962. (Box 50)
    - Jeremiah: The Call of the Prophet; The Message of the Prophet; and The Penultiamte Word. Üsküdar, Turkey: Near East Mission (United Church Board for World Ministries), 1966. (Box 50)
    - "Jeremiah and Moses: Further Observations." Journal of Biblical Literature 85/1 (1966): 17–27. (Box 50)
    - "The Recovery of Poetic Passages of Jeremiah." Journal of Biblical Literature 85/4 (1966): 401–435. (Box 50)
    - "Is the Bible Here to Stay? — Thoughts on Theological Renewal in the Twentieth Century." Lecture given at the University Christian Center Forum. Beirut, Lebanon, 1966. (Box 50)
    - "Chiasmus, the Key to Hosea XII 3–6." Vetus Testamentum 16/1 (1966): 53–64. (Box 50)
    - "Jeremiah XXXI 22b Reconsidered: 'The Woman Encompasses the Man'." Vetus Testamentum 16/2 (1966): 236–239. (Box 50)
    - "God's Crowning Self-Expression." The Alumni Bulletin: Bangor Theological Seminary 43/1 (January 1968): 6–10. (Box 50)
    - Zionism—Judaism: Is the Old Testament Zionist? Beirut, Lebanon: University Christian Center, 1968. (Box 50)
    - "Review of Das Problem der Urrolle by C. Rietzschel." Vetus Testamentum 18/3 (1968): 400–405. (Box 50)
    - "Short Notes: The 'Young Camel' and 'Wild Ass' in Jeremiah II 23–25." Vetus Testamentum 18/2 (1968): 256–260. (Box 50)
    - "Isaiah III 10–11: An Archaic Wisdom Passage." Vetus Testamentum 18/4 (1968): 481–487. (Box 50)
    - "Teaching Old Testament in an Arab Country." Harvard Divinity Bulletin 1/2 (Winter 1968): 12–14. (Box 50)
    - "A Biblical View of History." Lecture given at the University Christian Center. Beirut, Lebanon, 1970. (Box 50)
    - "Form and Word-Play in David's Lament Over Saul and Jonathan." Vetus Testamentum 20/2 (1970): 153–189. (Box 50)
    - "Once more, LANAK = `TIN', Amos VII 7-8." Vetus Testamentum 20/4 (October 1970): 492-494. (Box 50)
    - "Amos VI IB: a suggested solution." Vetus Testamentum 22/4 (January 1972): 107-110. (Box 50)
    - "The Covenant with the Patriarchs Overturned: Jeremiah's Intention in 'Terror on Every Side' (Jer 20:1–6)." Journal of Biblical Literature 91/3 (1972): 305–320. (Box 50)
    - "Resolved: That Both Early Judaism and Early Christianity are Equally Heresies of Biblical Faith: Torah." Lecture delivered at Colloquium, New England SBL/CBA, 23 January 1973. (Box 50)
    - "Work Sheet—Fresh Exegeses in Jeremiah." [No publication information.] February 1975. (Box 50)
    - "Review of Prophet, People, and the Word of Yahweh by John Maclennon Berridge." Journal of Biblical Literature [journal volume and/or number unknown] (1971): 250–251. (Box 50)
    - "God's Almost Chosen People." Lecture given at UCC & Meth Ch'es. 4 July 1976. (Box 50)
    - "Our hermeneutical dilemma I: masculine oriented language." Theological Markings (1980): 9-20. (Box 50)
    - "Our hermeneutical dilemma II: the political experience of Israel." Theological Markings (1980): 21-23. (Box 50)
    - "Bible studies." United Church of Christ: Fourteenth General Synod, June 24-28, 1983. Pittsburgh, 1983. (Box 50)
    - A Concise Hebrew and Aramaic Lexicon of the Old Testament. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1971. (Box 50)
    - Jeremiah: Spokesman Out of Time. Philadelphia: United Church Press, 1974. (Box 51)
    - The Architecture of Jeremiah 1-20. Lewisburg: Bucknell University Press, 1976. (Box 51)
    - Jeremiah 1, A Commentary on the Book of the Prophet Jeremiah: Chapters 1–25. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1986. (Box 51)
    - Isaiah: A Scroll of a Prophetic Heritage. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1978. (Box 52)
    - Jeremiah 2, A Commentary on the Book of the Prophet Jeremiah: Chapters 26– 52. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 1989. (Box 52)
    - Jeremiah: A Fresh Reading. New York: Pilgrim Press, 1990. (Box 52)
    - The Psalms Through Three Thousand Years. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 1993. (Box 53)
    - Long Ago God Spoke: How Christians May Hear the Old Testament Today. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 1995. (Box 53)
    - Unbound By Time: Isaiah Still Speaks. Cambridge, MA: Cowley Publications, 2002. (Box 53)
  - Horr, George Edwin
    - "The Book of the Law Found (2 Chronicles xxxiv: 14-33)". In History, Prophecy, and Gospel. Expository Sermons on the International Sunday-School Lesson for 1891, edited by E. Benjamin Andrews, 218-227. Boston: Silver, Burdett, and Company, 1891. (Box 54)
    - "Timely Admonition (Proverbs xxiii: 15-23)". In Gospel from Two Testaments. Sermons on the International Sunday-School Lessons for 1893, edited by E. Benjamin Andrews. Providence: Press of E. A. Johnson and Company, 1892. (Box 54)
    - Hid in the Heart: Scriptures That a Child of Ten Should Know. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1904. (Box 54)
    - The Training of the Chosen People. Boston: Bible Study Publishing, 1906. (Box 54)
    - Baptist Organization in the Light of History: an address before the Boston Baptist Ministers' Conference, April 22, 1907. Reprinted from the Watchman. [no publishing information] (Box 54)
    - The Great Ministry. Boston: Bible Study Publishing, 1907. (Box 54)
    - "Butler and Newman on Religious Certitude." The Harvard Theological Review 1 (July 1908): 346–61. (Box 54)
    - "Intra Portas." Hymn #32 in Prospectus of the Annotated Christian Hymnal, edited by Gilbert Harney and H.J. Storer. Boston: Stanhope Press, F.H. Gilson Co., 1912. (Box 54)
    - The Bible and the Christian Faith: an essay read before the Conference of Baptist Ministers in Massachusetts, Springfield October 29, 1912. s.l.: The Conference, [1912]. (Box 54)
    - Address of President George Edwin Horr on the Record at Newton: Not an "S.O.S." [no publication information] 1917. (Box 54)
    - The Christian Faith and Eternal Life: The Ingersoll Lecture, 1923. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1923. (Box 54)
  - Hovey, Alvah
    - An Inaugural address delivered before the Newton Theological Institution, June 28, 1854. Boston: J.M. Hewes, 1854. (Box 55)
    - The Christian pastor, his work and the needful preparation. Boston: Gould & Lincoln, 1857. (Box 55)
    - The state of the impenitent dead. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1859. (Box 55)
    - Outlines of Christian theology for the use of students in the Newton Theological Institution. Boston: Geo. C. Rand and Avery, 1861. (Box 55)
    - Close communion. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, [1862]. (Also published by Baptist Quarterly Review, 19 (1862): 133-168) (Box 55)
    - Outlines of Christian theology for the use of students in the Newton Theological Institution. Boston: Geo. C. Rand and Avery, 1866. (Box 56)
    - "Sermon: Withstanding Error By Truth" (May 1868). (Box 56)
    - Outlines of Christian theology for the use of students in the Newton Theological Institution. Providence: Providence Press Co., 1870. (Box 56)
    - State of men after death. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1874. (Box 56)
    - Christian Ethics for the use of students in the Newton Theological Institution. Boston: Printed by Rand, Avery, and Co, 1875. (Box 56)
    - Historical address delivered at the fiftieth anniversary of the Newton Theological Institution, June 8, 1875. Boston: Wright and Potter, 1875. (Box 55)
    - The state of the impenitent dead. Boston: D. Lothrop & Co, 1875. (Box 57)
    - "Progress of a century: the Baptists in 1776 and 1876." Baptist Quarterly (October 1876): 1-23. (Also published by American Baptist Publication Society) (Box 55)
    - Progress of a century: the Baptists in 1776 and 1876. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1876. (Box 55)
    - Manual of Systematic Theology and Christian Ethics. Boston: G. J. Stiles, 1877. (Box 57)
    - Manual of Systematic Theology and Christian Ethics. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1880. (Box 57)
    - The holy supper: in history and scripture. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1880. (Box 55)
    - Notes on church polity for the use of students in the Newton Theological Institution. Boston: G. J. Stiles, Printer, 1883. (cataloged as Pam. 9 no.24) (Box 58)
    - "Bible Wine: The Meaning of Yayin and Oinos in scripture." Baptist Quarterly Review 9 (April 1887): 151–180. (Box 58)
    - "What was the "Fruit of the Vine" which Jesus gave His disciples at the institution of the supper?" Baptist Quarterly Review 9 (July 1887): 285-303. (Box 58)
    - "Address by President Hovey." In In memory of Oakman Sprague Stearns, D.D., 7-25. Boston: Silver, Burdett and Co., [1893]. (Box 58)
    - Problems of the Bible and Philosophy. Watchman Extra (reprinted from The Watchman, June 13 and 20, 1895). (Box 58)
    - The Worth of Prayer. No. 492. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, [1896]. (Also published in The Watchman [July 9, 16, 1896]). (Box 58)
    - Syllabus of Christian apologetics. Printed for the author's class. Boston: Press of John Youngjohn, 1899. (Box 58)
    - Barnas Sears: A Christian Educator, His Life and Work. New York: Silver, Burdett & Co., 1902. (Box 58)
    - Manual of Christian Theology (F. H. Eveleth and U Tha Din, Trans.). Rngoon: American Baptist Mission Press, 1906. (Box 58)
    - "All Day With God." [Hymn, no publication information given.], no date (Box 58)
    - "Baptism and the Good Conscience." (Reprinted from the columns of the Christian Standard [Cincinnati].), no date (Box 58)
    - "The Resurrection of the Dead." Baptist Quarterly Review., no date (Box 58)
    - An epitome of textual criticism of the New Testament. Printed for the author's class. Boston: Press of John Youngjohn., no date (Box 58)
    - Election. No. 105. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society., no date (Box 58)
    - Evils of infant baptism. Philadelphia: The Bible and Publication Society., no date (Box 58)
    - Future Punishment. No. 62. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society., no date (Box 58)
    - How and Why Should I Give. No. 33. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society., no date (Box 58)
    - Syllabus of theological propaedeutics. Printed for the author's class. Boston: Silver, Burdett and Co., no date (Box 58)
    - The Christian Teaching of Old Testament Offerings. Document no. 1. Commission on Systematic Beneficence., no date (Box 58)
    - Biography and Bibliography of Alvah Hovey., no date (Box 58)
  - Hunt, Mary E
    - editor, A Guide for Women in Religion: Making Your Way from A to Z. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2004. (Box 33)
  - Ives, Hilda Libby